

Location: New York City
Telephone: +1 (347) 498-5369
Email: simon@hypertexthero.com
Portfolio: hypertexthero.com/work
Photographs: simongriffee.com/stories

Summary

I enjoy learning and absorbing information from different fields to help solve problems, keep my brain whirring and, with any luck, pass on knowledge to future generations.

With over a decade of professional graphic and web design experience while travelling extensively around the world and living in Brazil, Tunisia, Italy, England and the United States I have learned to speak and write in: **English** and **Portuguese** fluently, **Italian** well, **French** and **Spanish** in a somewhat amusing way. Using these together with **visual** and **programming languages** I have managed to:

- Increase funding for and cooperation between international organizations.
- Save people time and make them happier when using computers.
- Help groups and individuals with hands-on design, coding, editing, brainstorming and critique.

I'm based in and ♥ New York City.

Experience

Information Systems Officer, International Plant Protection Convention (IPPC) Food and Agriculture Organization, United Nations, Rome, Italy, June 2009–Present: Helped increase funding from donors, increase number of contracting parties to the convention and increase the general public's awareness of its work while making people using computers there happier. Provided design support and technical advice on the creation and evolution of websites and other digital media as well as hands-on design and coding work at all stages. Organized photo groups and food and wine tasting on Fridays.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer · Hypertexthero, Worldwide, 2005–Present: Completed a variety of web and print projects for clients around the world, from large companies in London and internet startups in the Bay Area to non-profits and United Nations agencies in Rome.

Web & Graphic Designer · *Acotel Group S.p.A, Rome, Italy, 2003–2004:*Created the first web standards based website design project in Italy.
Completed identity design projects, marketing and advertising multimedia campaigns.

Freelance Web & Graphic Designer

European Artisans, Various, Rome, Italy, 1999–2003: Freelance designer for an internet startup and various clients.

Education

I learned to work with computers with computer games. I learned graphic design from books, interfaces, posters and films by designers like Milton Glaser, Susan Kare and Saul Bass. I learned HTML and CSS by viewing the source of websites, searching with Google and reading Jeffrey Zeldman's Designing With Web Standards.

I learned user experience, usability and accessibility principles from The Cluetrain Manifesto, Don't Make Me Think and Jacob Nielsen's Alertbox column. I learned photography by taking and looking at photographs. I learned to cook and to eat in Italy. I've been learning some Python and enjoyed meeting Alex Martelli in Florence in 2013.

Magnum Photos Workshops · Cortona 2011, Wolverhampton 2012, Paris 2013
Per Volquartz Workshop · Joshua Tree, California 2007
Stanford University, 2006 · Concept Design Workshop at Stanford University's d.school Bournemouth University, 1996–1999 · B.A. with Honours in Creative Advertising
Arts University Bournemouth, 1997–1998 · City & Guilds Diploma with Distinction in Photography

Skills & Tools

Web development: Wireframing in HTML & CSS client-side code that usually ends up in production. Some JavaScript and Python.

User experience design, usability, accessibility: Fast, simple interfaces and good writing over excessive style.

Photography: Candid photography, usually on the street using Leica rangefinder cameras and Fuji and Ricoh compacts. I want a better, more affordable camera for photography students and better editing software.

Software: Web browsers (Firefox and Chrome) and their developer tools, Textmate and a Terminal prompt, Sketch, Lightroom, Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign. I have experience with Python and Django that I also use to edit hypertexthero.com on a local development server that is then published with rsync and version controlled with Git and GitHub. I also know a bit of Ruby and Jekyll, some Apache and Nginx configuration, a tiny bit of MySQL, PostgreSQL and SQLite, and a little Unix system administration.

Interests

Communication, information, photography, travel, independent web, open source & open internet, philosophy, typography, art history, nature, astronomy, music, (blues guitar, jazz, classical), computer simulations, vintage aeroplanes, basketball.